coc.org 2018-05-02

# Legal and Privacy Policy | COC

**Legal and Privacy Policy**

Here you'll find information about our materials reuse policy, our copyright statement, and about our commitment to ensuring the privacy of your personal information, such as your full name, address, e-mail address, telephone number or other identifying information. You will find information on

  * Copyright Notice

  * Permission Policy

  * Donor Privacy Policy

  * Changes to our Policy

  * Education for Justice Website Participants Only

  * Computer Services

  * Contact Us

**Copyright Notice**

Published materials of the Center of Concern and our web site materials - text, graphics, layout and presentation are copyrighted by the Center. All rights are reserved.  
Permission is granted to download and print materials from this web site for the purposes of viewing, reading and retaining the reference for personal use. Any other copying, distribution, retransmission, or modification of this information or materials on this site, without the permission of the Center of Concern is strictly prohibited.

**Permission Policy**

All materials published to [www.coc.org](http://www.coc.org/) are copyrighted or are used with permission of the original copyright holder. As such, they may not be reused without express permission from the Center of Concern.  
We normally will give permission to reprint or use our materials when requested in writing. Please contact us stating:  
1\. what you intend to use,  
2\. how it will be used, and  
3\. for what time period

After receiving permission, we require that you acknowledge the Center of Concern as the source of the material, and, if possible, note our web site address [www.coc.org](http://www.coc.org/) either in printed materials or via a link in electronically published materials.

We also request that you send us a copy for our archives of the material as you've used it.

Please contact the Director of Administration who manages permission requests for the Center of Concern.

Center of Concern  
Director of Administration  
1225 Otis St. NE  
Washington DC. 20017-2516  
E-mail: [communications@coc.org](mailto:communications@coc.org)

**Donor  Privacy Policy**

Center of Concern (Center) uses personal information that donors provide, whether for on-line or off-line donation, solely to fulfill the contractual and regulatory obligations resulting from the donation, e.g., acknowledging the donation to the donor and honoree or survivor in the case of an honorific or memorial donation; recording the donation in accounting and other internal records; and reporting the donation for tax purposes, depending on the scale and scope.

The Center does not share personal information for other reasons unless the donor gives express written permission for it to do so, and then only according to the scale and scope for such permission. The Center honors all requests from donors to remain anonymous, except for reporting obligations to tax authorities; in such cases, it makes available for public inspection a redacted version of its Internal Revenue Service Form 990 that omits this personal information.

The Center does not sell or share donor lists. The Center periodically may contact donors who supply it with their postal address and/or e-mail address for solicitation purposes and/or to share information regarding resources, program performance, and upcoming events. The Center makes available to all donors an option to receive a single contact annually. The Center honors all requests for removal from mailing lists, regardless of the means for the request, including e-mail, postal mail, telephone, or in-person communication.

The Center does not participate in telephone fundraising activities, directly or through third parties. When the Center contacts donors via telephone, it does so solely regarding previous donations.

To contact the Center regarding its policies and procedures for protecting personal information, or to give instructions regarding the Center’s use of your personal information, please use one of the following means:

  1. Postal address: 

Center of Concern  
1225 Otis Street N.E.  
Washington, DC 20017

  2. Telephone:  +1 (202-) 635-2757 between 9:30 a.m. and 5 p.m. EST, Monday-Friday.
  3. Email: [coc@coc.org](mailto:coc@coc.org)

**Why does the Center of Concern ask for my information?**

In order to participate in some activities, you might be asked to provide some personal information. This could be in connection with any one or combination of the following:

  * subscription to the Center of Concern newsletter
  * content submissions, community postings (i.e., forums or bulletin boards), comments and suggestions or voting
  * sending personalized faxes or e-mail messages when participating in an online action

**What information does the Center of Concern collect?**

We do not collect personal information from our visitors other than what is supplied to us on a voluntary basis. Aggregate information about our site visitors, such as pages viewed, browsers used, and documents downloaded, is collected in our web server logs. Domain names or IP addresses of site visitors may also be collected but these addresses are not traceable to any one individual. This aggregate information is used solely in the pursuit of helping us improve our web site.

**Does the Center of Concern use cookies?**

Yes, while we use cookies for a variety of purposes, we do not use cookies to collect personal information about site visitors. The site does use cookies in our online store as well as in the Education for Justice area of the site. Please see the specific policies for that service below.

A "cookie" is a tiny element of data that our site can send to your browser which may then be stored on your hard drive. Cookies that are sent to your browser by our site are only readable by the Center of Concern and are never shared with any other site. If you are concerned about your privacy and the use of cookie technology on the Center of Concern you may set your web browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. You may also set your browser to refuse the cookies our site attempts to send you. Should you decide not to accept cookies from the Center of Concern you may limit the functionality we can provide when you visit our site.

**How will the Center of Concern use the information I provide?**

We will always explain the extent of its use at the time you are asked to provide personal information. If you do not want this information to be collected or used by us for these purposes, you can simply "opt out." Under certain circumstances, opting out may prevent your participation in activities for which personal information is needed, such as the participation in online actions or subscription to the Center of Concern newsletter.

**Does the Center of Concern rent, sell or trade my information?**

The Center of Concern occasionally makes the names and postal addresses of donors available to reputable, like-minded advocacy organizations. We never exchange our donors' e-mail addresses. If you are a Center of Concern donor and you DO NOT wish to have your information exchanged with other organizations please contact us:

1\. Send correspondence to the following postal address:  
Center of Concern  
1225 Otis Street N.E.  
Washington, DC 20017

2\. Call us at 202-635-2757 between 9:30 a.m. and 5 p.m. EST, Monday - Friday.

If you are a Center donor or you have made a purchase from our online store that has not yet been shipped, you can update your information through one of the following methods:

1\. Send correspondence to the following postal address:  
Center of Concern  
1225 Otis Street N.E.  
Washington, DC 20017

2\. Call us at 202-635-2757 between 9:30 a.m. and 5 p.m. EST, Monday - Friday.

3\. E-mail [communications@coc.org](mailto:communications@coc.org)

You can change the information associated with your online subscriptions by visiting our subscription center. You will need the e-mail address at which you receive your mailings to access your account.

**How do I know my credit card information is secure?**

The Center of Concern uses secure server software (SSL) that is the industry standard and is among the best software available today for secure commerce transactions. It encrypts all of your personal information, including credit card number, name and address, so that it cannot be read as the information travels over the Internet. Under the Fair Credit Billing Act, your bank cannot hold you liable for more than $50.00 of fraudulent charges. In the event of an unauthorized charge to your credit card you must 1) write to the creditor at the address given for "billing inquiries," not the address for sending your payments, and include your name, address, account number and a description of the billing error, 2) send your letter so that it reaches the creditor within 60 days after the first bill containing the error was mailed to you.

**What do I do if I have questions that aren't answered here?**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or your dealings with this website, please contact us.

**Changes to our Policy**

The Center of Concern reserves the right to change these policies at its sole discretion without any obligation, to modify or correct errors and omissions within the web site. Changes to this policy will always be posted and public. If any changes are made to the type of information we collect or to the ways in which we use that information, clear, specific instructions will be provided on how you may opt out of new practices.

_Last Updated July 2016_
